Welcome to this expense agent uh video
series. In this video, we'll try to
explain much more about perdm, how you
can calculate and how you can expose
your PDM allowances in expense agent.
So, uh perdm can be really complicated
calculation because it depends from
country to country different rules how
you can calculate and so on. So, we try
to make uh almost all possible
combination in a setup. you will have uh
driven uh set of vizard configuration
vizard to make this easier. But if you
want to adjust with much more details to
be 100% compliant with your country
rules, you can go to express agent setup
and adjust all configuration there. So
you will find that we have three
different perdm calculation. You have 24
hours rolling period. So this is from uh
6:00 a.m. until the next 6 a.m. and so
on. So this is how system is calculating
or if you have only full calendar day
and first and last day will be
calculated based on some percent then if
you have over date and then for partial
uh day rules if you are not whole day on
a trip you have flat percentage of full
rate or based on eligible hours. So you
can see so many uh combinations and then
all these calculation can be based on a
minimum hours for full perdm, minimum
hours for partial perdm, percentage or
partial perdm and even more after that
if you had for example breakfast, lunch
or dinner and u you have uh by company
policy some reduction. So if you had
this in a conference so you had a lunch
in a conference you can just mark that
you had a lunch this day and system will
automatically use for configure percent
uh for this one day. So you can see this
is complex but we try to simplify as
more as possible and now you will see
how it works really simple in a new web
app. Yeah. So I'm in the expense agent
web application and I have already added
a paird report and I'm just going to go
to the expense. I'm going to open it and
I'm just going to try to zoom in. I'm
able to see this expense that I just
added for my colleague here actually
Alexander Totovich. U the agent detects
a perdm trip when um an expense is
provided as an itinerary. You can
actually see here in this case the
itinerary is from the 29th of September
flying from Belgrade via via Frankfurt
to London. And of course, so of course
we also have the trip back on the 2nd of
October. The agent detects that this is
an itinerary expense and it's going to
categorize this as uh a pair DM expense.
So if I go back then you can actually
see that it detected the merchant which
is air pass the total amount the date
for the pdm expense of course the
business description the the expense
description the payment means and the
categorization of course is perdm and if
I go to the travel tab you can actually
see that the agent seamlessly detected
the location of this expense in this
case it's UK other because this is what
I set up in business central. So it
detected actually that I traveled to
London and that's where I spent most of
the days from Serbia and then went back.
It also detected the start time of this
um expense but also the end time of this
period. And as my also my colleague
mentioned here uh in the previous slide,
we talked about these meal reductions
that your users can actually pick based
on yeah the different meals of the day
that they received at the conference for
example. So I can actually go into an
edit mode and let's say that I flew to
London for a conference and now I'm just
doing my expenses and of course I want
to make sure that all the data is uh
correct and on Monday the 30th of
September breakfast,
lunch and dinner was provided. I'm just
going to save the changes and as soon as
uh the changes are saved then you can
actually see that the total amount of
the expense which was initially 232
uh pounds was actually decreased to 187
and 0.92 because of the meals reduction.
Uh so that's that's pretty much how it
works. Uh now let's see what you can
actually do on the admin side of uh
Business Central.
As an admin, I can actually go to the
expense agent avatar here on the right
side of the screen. I can actually click
on the settings button and then I will
navigate to the perdm
details tab. So we have this tab now in
the expense agent wizard called perdm
expenses and you can actually set up
this calculation. So my per day
calculation is based on a full calendar
day [snorts] and then you can actually
uh you know um set up your flat rate or
like your your rate and also the meals
reduction that I was talking about and
this can be set up here and in this case
it was set up to 15%. So basically
whenever you um whatever you set here
the percentage then it's going to be
deducted for the from the total perdm
allowance per uh per trip.
This is pretty much it about uh the
admin section in the expense agent in
the business central admin section.
Thank you. Thank you Cladio. So as you
can see uh we completely simplify a
really complicated area PDM. So you can
really easy as submitter you can really
easy just upload your itinary system
will calculate everything based on
starting ending date uh destinations uh
starting actually uh address and
destination everything done
automatically.
So this is definitely really simplified.
So we hope you will use this uh
functionality in the B central and thank
you for watching this video.